esc.edu 2016-06-06

# Web Privacy Policy - SUNY Empire State College | Policies, Procedures and Guidelines | SUNY Empire State College

## Sponsor:

| Information Technology Services   
---|---  
  
## Contact:

| Chief Information Officer and Vice President for Information Technology Services  
  
## Category:

|  Computer and Other Integrated Technology Related Policies   
  
## Number:

| 700.006  
  
## Effective Date:

| 06/14/2002  
  
## Review Date:

| 07/01/2013  
  
## Implementation History:

| Approved: June 14, 2002 under the title “SUNY Empire State College Privacy Policy” Revised: January 18, 2008 and title changed to “Web Privacy Policy”   
  
## Keywords:

| Web Privacy Policy  
  
## Background Information:

|   
  
## Purpose

This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.

## Definitions

The following definitions apply to, and appear in italics, in this policy:

 ** _Personal information_** : For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.  
 **  
 _User_** : shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State Technology

## Statements

Empire State College is committed to protecting your privacy while making it easier and more efficient to interact with our college. You can navigate through much of the college's website without giving us any information about yourself. Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this commitment to privacy explains our online information practices. 

We do not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an email, completing an online form or completing the online application **.**

This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.

#### **Information Collected Automatically When You Visit this Website**

When visiting this website, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

  * user client hostname: the hostname or Internet Protocol address of the user requesting access to a college website
  * HTTP header, "user agent": the type of browser, its version, and the operating system on which the browser is running
  * HTTP header, "referrer":  specifies the webpage from which the user accessed the current webpage
  * system date: date and time of the user's request
  * full request: exact request the user made
  * status: status code the server returned to the user
  * content length: content length, in bytes, of the document sent to the user
  * method: request method used
  * Universal Resource Identifier (URI): location of a resource on the server
  * Query string of the URI: anything after the question mark in a URI
  * protocol: transport protocol and the version used
  * processing time: time, in milliseconds, it took for the server to process the request
  * host header: hostname of the requested file, e.g., [www.esc.edu](http://www.esc.edu/)
  * cookies: name of any cookie used.

None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute _personal information_ by the [Internet Security and Privacy Act](http://www.its.ny.gov/tables/privacy_policy).

In addition to the above-mentioned information, when you access a password-protected part of the website, your username is collected automatically. 

All information that is collected automatically is used to improve our Web content, to investigate possible problems and in general to help us understand how you are interacting with our website. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users. The information is not collected for commercial purposes and the college does not sell or otherwise distribute the information collected from the website for commercial purposes.

#### Information Collected When You E-mail our Webmaster or Complete a Transaction

If you send an email to our Web mananger, your email address and the contents of your message are collected. These are used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this website or to forward your message to someone who can help you. We do not disclose your email address to any person or organization outside the college.

If you voluntarily complete an online form, the _personal information_ you provide will be retained in a way that is appropriate to complete your transaction. We do not knowingly collect _personal information_ from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. Caution: if you submit _personal information_ in an email, the information will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or state law, be subject to public access.

#### Cookies

Cookies are simple text files stored on your Web browser to provide a means of distinguishing among users of this website. The use of cookies is a standard practice among Internet websites. To better serve you, we may use persistent and/or session cookies to enhance or customize your visit to this website. Persistent and session cookies that are created automatically on the device you use to access this website do not contain _personal information_ and do not compromise your privacy or security. We may use the cookie feature to store a randomly generated identifying tag on the device you use to access this website. A session cookie is normally erased during operation of your browser or when your browser is closed. Some Web browsers retain session cookies by default; you can adjust your browser settings to ensure that session cookies are deleted. A persistent cookie remains on your computer until you decide to delete it. We use persistent cookies on some parts of our website to gather nonpersonal statistical data when you visit our website.

The software and hardware you use to access the website allows you to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies. Refusing or deleting these cookies may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of this website.

#### Information and Choice

As noted above, Empire State College does not collect any _personal information_ about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an email, responding to a survey, or completing an online form. You may choose not to send us an email, respond to a survey, or complete an online form. While your choice not to participate in these activities may limit your ability to receive specific services or products through this website, it will not normally have an impact on your ability to take advantage of other features of the website, including browsing or downloading information.

#### Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Website

The collection of information through this website and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. Empire State College will only collect _personal information_ through this website or disclose _personal information_ collected through this website if the _user_ has consented to the collection or disclosure of such _personal information_. The voluntary disclosure of _personal information_ to Empire State College by the user, whether solicited or unsolicited, constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by Empire State College for the purposes for which the _user_ disclosed the information to Empire State College, as was reasonably ascertainable from the nature and terms of the disclosure.

However, Empire State College may collect or disclose _personal information_ without consent if the collection or disclosure is: 1. necessary to perform the statutory duties of Empire State College, or necessary for Empire State College to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; 2. made pursuant to a court order or by law; 3. for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or 4. of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person. 

Further, the disclosure of information, including _personal information_ , collected through this website is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. 

Empire State College may disclose _personal information_ to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to Empire State College’s information technology assets.

#### Retention of Information Collected Through this Website

The information collected through this website is retained by Empire State College in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State Arts and Cultural Affairs Law. Information on the requirements of the Arts and Cultural Affairs Law may be found at [www.archives.nysed.gov/a/records/mr_laws_state.shtml](http://www.archives.nysed.gov/a/records/mr_laws_state.shtml). In general, the Internet services logs of Empire State College, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of college services provided through this website, are retained in accordance with the records retention and disposition schedule established for the records of the Office of Educational Technology. Information, including _personal information_ , that you submit in an email or when you complete a survey, registration form or order form is retained in accordance with the records retention and disposition schedule established for the records of the program unit to which you submitted the information. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact listed in this policy.

#### Access to and Correction of _Personal Information_ Collected Through this Website

Any _user_ may submit a request to the Empire State College privacy compliance officer to determine whether _personal information_ pertaining to that _user_ has been collected through this website. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy compliance officer is:

Privacy Compliance Officer  
Empire State College  
3 Union Avenue  
Saratoga Springs, NY 12866

The privacy compliance officer shall, within five business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the _personal information_ ; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than 30 days from the date of the acknowledgment. 

In the event that Empire State College has collected _personal information_ pertaining to a _user_ through the college website and that information is to be provided to the _user_ pursuant to the user’s request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the _user_ of his or her right to request that the _personal information_ be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the Public Officers Law.

#### Confidentiality and Integrity of _Personal Information_ Collected Through this Website

Empire State College is strongly committed to protecting _personal information_ collected through this website against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, Empire State College limits employee access to _personal information_ collected through this website to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of _personal information_.

In addition, Empire State College has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, monitoring, auditing and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day operations of this website as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

For website security purposes and to maintain the availability of the website for all users, Empire State College employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage this website.

#### Disclaimer

The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through this website.

#### Contact Information

For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please email [privacypolicy@esc.edu](mailto:privacypolicy@esc.edu)  
or write  
Privacy Compliance Officer   
Empire State College   
3 Union Avenue   
Saratoga Springs, NY 12866

## Applicable Legislation and Regulations

This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.

## Related References, Policies, Procedures, Forms and Appendices

Password and Information Security Practices at Empire State College

Web Presence and Publishing Policy - SUNY Empire State College
